Guide to the Douglas Fitzgerald Dowd papers, 1947-2007.
Dowd, Douglas Fitzgerald papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Douglas Fitzgerald Dowd papers, 1947-2007.
14-10-4252
Dowd, Douglas Fitzgerald,
4.4 cubic feet, 230 GB
Correspondence, manuscripts, printed material, newspapers, publications, legal documents, audio/visual recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials relating to Dowd's career and writings. Includes correspondence, publications and articles by Dowd and others on various political economic topics, book drafts, book reviews written by Dowd and reviews by others of Dowd's books, materials relating to Dowd's activism some relating to anti-Vietnam war activities and other injustices, including copies of FBI and CIA files. CDs, video, and audio materials relating to Dowd's career. Also, items relating to Thorstein Veblen.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Political economist and activist. He taught at Cornell University and served as advisor to the Students for a Democratic Society. In the 1968 US presidential election he was one of the nominees for Vice President as a member of the Peace and Freedom Party.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Materials relating to Dowd's career and writings. Includes correspondence, publications and articles by Dowd and others on various political economic topics, book drafts, book reviews written by Dowd and reviews by others of Dowd's books, materials relating to Dowd's activism some relating to anti-Vietnam war activities and other injustices, including copies of FBI and CIA files. CDs, video, and audio materials relating to Dowd's career. Also, items relating to Thorstein Veblen. Also digital files containing documents, papers, articles, photographs, correspondence of Dowd's as well as audio and video of Dowd's talks and course material. Also copies of the content that appeared on dougdowd.org website managed by Michael Slaughter before it was shut down.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Dowd, Douglas Fitzgerald, 1919-; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929.; Students for a Democratic Society.; Union for Radical Political Economics.
Subjects:
Capitalism.; Economics.; Economics; Political activists.; Socialism.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Dowd testimony before Committee on Banking and Currency, 1969-04-30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dowd data, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- San Jose State University files, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Misc., 1978, 2000, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Doug/Fred book, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CIA file on Dowd, 1 of 2, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CIA file on Dowd, 2 of 2, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- FBI file on Dowd, 1 of 2, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- FBI file on Dowd, 2 of 2, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photos, photocopies, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Interview with Paul Sweezy, 1986-11-19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ideas, "The Other Depression", parts I-IV, Canadian Broadcasting Corp., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dowd CV, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Misc. articles not by Dowd, 1969-2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Dowd Thesis, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Doctrine Notes, etc., Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence found grouped together, 1947-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1949-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1998-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Flyers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Talks, 2003, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Seattle conspiracy defense fund, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- East bay socialist school, winter term, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dowd statement regarding Labor and Justice Dept., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Berrigan items, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Book covers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lecture notes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Unsorted items, 1970's-2000's (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Newspapers, 1960's-1980's (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Newspapers, 1965-2005 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 1994, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Articles/publications by Dowd, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Includes items relating to Thorstein Veblen
- Book reviews for and by Dowd, 1950's-1960's (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Book reviews for and by Dowd, 19701970's (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Book reviews for and by Dowd, 1980's-2000's (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Book draft: Chapter 1, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Capitalism and its economics, a critical history
- Book draft: Chapter 2, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Book draft: Chapter 3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Book draft: Chapter 4, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Book draft: Chapter 5, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Book draft: Chapter 6, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Book draft: Chapter 7, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Book draft: Appendix, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Book draft: Epilogue/prologue, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Unsorted book draft material, 1 of 3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Unsorted book draft material, 2 of 3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Unsorted book draft material, 3 of 3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Papers by Dowd, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Papers by Dowd, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Papers by Dowd, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- VHS and cassette tapes, DVD's and CD's, Unknown date (Box 4)
- Dowd articles in publications, 1966-2001 (Box 5)